Mob No: 9970108466

Email Id: cakrantipawar@gmail.com

Profile Summary:

Competent and resourceful Chartered Accountant with over 10 years of experience and excellent skills in handling financial reporting, taxation, corporate finance, auditing and other accounting activities. Highly skilled in maintaining accounting records and preparing accounts and management information for assigned areas. Easy going by nature and able to work with all members of staff regarding finance issues to resolve problems. Presently seeking a professional and satisfying role in a organization.

Career History:

Jan 2020 to May 2020: Future Consumer Limited, Lead – Indirect taxation

- Review and filing of monthly GST returns for 21 states
- Had work on the assignment of GST credit reconciliation for a company from FY 2017 18 to FY 2019 20 and streamline GST GL's for 21 states with credit appearing on GST portal
- Preparing the GST credit reconciliation report to be communicated to operation team
- Handling preparation of MIS reports and GST GL reconciliation statements
- Conducting review of the current GST reports and make improvement in system or reports wherever needed
- Working on the E way bill and new GST return automation process
- Replying and compiling the details for communication received from government officials
- Assisting in compiling details for due diligence

<u>Aug 2018 to Dec 2019: Tata AIG General Insurance Company – Deputy Manager – Finance and accounts</u>

> Indirect tax

- Preparation and filing of monthly GST returns for 26 states
- Review of monthly purchase register and ensure input tax credit has been correctly accounted as per GST norms, if any changes needed then same has been communicated to respective person
- Preparation of monthly GST payable and GST receivable GL reconciliation registers
- Preparation of the cross charge working & credit reversal working
- Working on the GSTR 2A reconciliation and take corrective action to minimize the gap in GST credit as per GSTR 2A and credit as per books.
- Had lead the GSTR 9 and GSTR 9C compliance for FY 2017 18

Direct tax

- Review and supervision of the monthly TDS payment and quarterly TDS returns
- Working on the TDS defaults
- Preparation of the monthly TDS GL reconciliation statements
- Assist in compilation of the details for the assessment procedures
- Assist in tax audit and its report preparation

Other supportive work

- Working on the GL reports updates wherever needed and system automation improvement
- Preparing the KRA of teammates and guiding them to achieve them
- Communicating and assisting various accounting teammates so to ensure all the
 accounting done keeping all tax norms in mind and if there is any error it should
 be noticed & rectified
- Assist tax head in preparation of various PPT reports for management presentation

<u>Jan 2015 to Aug 2018: Radius corporate solution (P) Limited – Assistant Manager – Compliance</u>

> Accounts:

- Preparation of balance sheet and profit & loss statements for subsidiaries and consolidated one
- Finalization of the monthly/ quarterly/ annual books of accounts for clients
- Preparation of the reconciliation statements for various GL's basis on the applicable tax law

Direct tax:

- Preparation of the corporate tax returns for the clients from India, Australia, Singapore, UK and other part of the world
- Preparation of the tax audit reports and other tax audit works papers for Indian entities
- Preparation of monthly TDS summary report and TDS payment computations along with filing quarterly TDS returns.
- Preparation of the working for payment of advance tax for clients

> Indirect tax:

- Assisting tax manager in GST implementation process for clients in India
- Preparation of the GST health check report for clients base on the implementation done.
- Preparation and filing of monthly GST returns, handling the GST registrations and communications from departments for the clients.

> Supportive work:

- Assisting to Tax Manager in the management of a portfolio of Clients, delivering timely compliance services, analysis and documentation as agreed with the Tax Manager and, where appropriate, client
- Ensure appropriate support and assistance is sought by relevant affiliates in receiving countries and that those services are managed to maximum effect

From Nov 2010 to Dec 2014: Mehta Kothari & Company, Senior Executive

- Preparation and filings of Income tax returns & TDS returns for Companies, Firms, HUF's, Trusts and Individuals
- Leading the statutory audits for clients and preparing the audit working papers
- Finalization of books of accounts as per applicable standards and laws for clients along with preparing reconciliation statements for the various accounts.
- Preparation of balance sheets, P&L for companies, firm and individuals
- Preparation of the documents for Income tax or TDS assessments and appeals along with gathering of the relevant documents and information from the clients

From Feb 2007 to Sept 2009: Article assistant with V K Beswal & Associates & N T Rahalkar

& Company

Being a CA article assistant, had assist in audit, many direct tax and indirect tax compliance and also assist in preparation of the details for the assessments.

Academic Qualification

- Chartered Accountant, from ICAI- Mumbai Aug 2019
- CA PCE (Inter)- Mumbai May 2010
- B.Com, from R K Talreja College Mar 2009– Ulhasnagar (Mumbai University)

Personal details

Date of birth: 30th Dec 1988

Residential address: B, 402, Sai Ashish CHS, Village Road, Bhandup

(W) Language Known: Marathi, Hindi & English